# Ian Hundere

DevOps | SRE | Cloud | Platform Atlanta, GA | (512) 410-0083 ian.hunde.re | qithub.com/ianhundere | linkedin.com/in/ianhundere | ian@hunde.re

# Summary

I'm an enthusiastic problem solver with years of experience working with developers, IaaS (AWS), and multiple data sources to produce highly integrated solutions. Well experienced with version control, tool selection, and pipeline building. I have built several full-stack and front-end applications using Node.js, React, Express.js, MongoDB, and Tone.js. Personal projects include self-hosting a number of applications via a K3s Raspberry PI cluster, an assortment of Python scripts and configuring an advanced home automation network with open source tools.

### **Skills**

AWS, Kubernetes, Terraform, Linux, Bash, Python, Docker, Ansible, Git, Packer, Vagrant, Datadog, New Relic, Zabbix, Sumo Logic, Prometheus, Grafana, Helm, Consul, Vault, Flux, Argo CD, Gitlab CI, CircleCI, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB

# **Experience**

## DevOps Community of Practice Lead | Oddball | Atlanta, GA

October 2022 - Present

- Facilitate impromptu discussions and lessons learned to improve technical growth, effectiveness and velocity among fellow DevOps Engineers
- Coordinate and lead meetings surrounding shared cloud infrastructure across a variety of organizations, teams, and individuals to prioritize improvement/maintenance related tickets to be delegated by each teams' project managers

## DevOps Engineer | Oddball | Atlanta, GA

April 2022 – Present

- Develop and implement a custom GitHub Action using bash and Slack's Block Kit to detect Terraform drift providing detailed information as to what specific infrastructure resources (e.g. AWS, Datadog, etc) are out of sync
- Apply log processing rules (e.g. regex) to drop unwanted/noisy logs at both the deployment (e.g. podAnnotations) and Datadog agent level (e.g. globally via Helm)
- Create custom IAM permissions boundary to prevent privilege escalation and limit scope of IAM users and roles
- Resolve long running API routes (third-party services) by building secondary ASG and LB resources whereby problematic routes were rerouted using Nginx redirects and triggered on every build via Jenkins; short-term fix
- Move a Ruby based Sign-in Service controller from a monolith infrastructure (e.g. a containerized monolith hosted on dedicated EC2 instances deployed via Ansible and Jenkins) to a microservice infrastructure (e.g. deployed to EKS via Argo CD and GitHub Actions) to improve resiliency and availability

#### Cloud Infrastructure Engineer II | Revel Systems | Atlanta, GA

November 2020 – April 2022

- Lead effort to improve developer velocity by bundling monitoring (e.g. EKS, ECS, EC2, RDS etc.) with deployments through custom Terraform modules using the Datadog provider
- Rebuild GitLab Runner EKS cluster by improving its IaC, availability and disaster recovery through automation
- Develop a modular CLI bash script used by the entire Infrastructure team to do a variety of tasks such as accessing RDS per PCI standards with optional flags to list schemas, users, long running queries as well as pass valid SQL
- Build Ansible playbooks; for instance, to enable RDS IAM authentication and seed RDS instances with users/roles
- Increase developer velocity by assisting development teams with Terraform, GitLab CI/CD pipelines, AWS, \*nix, containerization, etc. including creating tools (e.g. Terraform modules, CI/CD templates, scripts) for them to use
- Mentor junior engineers through regular check-ins, postmortems surrounding their actions, and asking purposeful questions to further their understanding improving their velocity as an engineer

### DevOps Engineer | Artis Technologies, LLC | Atlanta, GA

February 2020 - October 2020

- Configure and maintain EKS clusters for multiple deployments
- Automate tasks with bash scripts, Kubernetes Jobs, Kubernetes CronJobs, and AWS Lambda functions
- Install, configure, and maintain Sumo Logic, Datadog, CloudWatch and New Relic to monitor site reliability, durability, integrity and confidentiality
- Implement CI/CD pipelines using CircleCI
- Performance tune pipelines to decrease deployment times by 60%

## Software Engineer, DevOps & Training Platforms | Itential, LLC | Atlanta, GA

January 2019 - February 2020

- Configure and automate Itential's learning environment used by internal employees, external customers, and potential customers using Ansible and Docker
- Improve the launch time of lab containers by 30%
- Create RESTful APIs using Express and Puppeteer to automate CRUD operations (e.g. student enrollment/unenrollment; brittle, not a good idea)
- Install and configure openLDAP, Netbox, Zabbix and Grafana

- Create and teach a variety of professional development to improve teachers' instruction efficacy at 7 campuses
- Identify technology integration competencies among instructional staff in collaboration with administrators to deliver effective coaching to accelerate the professional growth of adult learners
- Make decisions related to instructional technology acquisition and deployment to encourage student engagement and academic rigor

**Teacher, 4th and 5th grade** | Pflugerville Independent School District | Austin, TX August 2013 – June 2016

- Utilize diverse teaching strategies to effectively address each student's learning style and ability
- Create and maintain training resources used to certify 3rd party clients
- Demonstrate a strong degree of teamwork ethic by assisting in the coordination of weekly staff meetings

# Product Specialist Support | Apple Inc. | Austin, TX

September 2007 - August 2012

- Assist a number of companies (e.g. OfficeMax, Best Buy, etc.) with their support of Apple products
- Create and maintain training resources used to certify 3rd party clients
- Demonstrate a strong degree of teamwork ethic by assisting in the coordination of weekly staff meetings

## **Education**

DigitalCrafts | Full-Stack Web Development | Atlanta, GA Texas State University | Master in Education | San Marcos, TX University of Victoria | B.A. in History | Victoria, B.C., Canada September 2018 – January 2019 August 2010 – December 2012 September 2002 – August 2007